Guide to the Paul L. Holmer Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings of Holmer, Series I
  - Reviews by Holmer
    - Review of Kierkegaard and Radical Discipleship: A New Perspective (Vernard Eller. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1968) in Interpretation, 24.2: 263. (1 tear sheet, 1 letter from editorial staff at journal)., 1970 Apr (Box 25, Folder 386)
    - Review of Kierkegaard and Radical Discipleship: A New Perspective (Vernard Eller. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1968) in Journal for the Scientific Study of Religion, 9.1: 67-70. (1 manuscript, 1 postcard from the journal's book review editor)., 1970 Spring (Box 25, Folder 387)
    - Review of Restless Adventure: Essays on Contemporary Expressions of Existentialism (Roger L. Shinn, ed. New York: Charles Scribner's and Sons, 1968) in Religious Education, 65: 282-284. (1 typescript)., 1970 May-Jun (Box 25, Folder 388)
    - "Polanyi and Being Reasonable: Some Comments in Review of Intellect and Hope " a review of Intellect and Hope: Essays in the Thought of Michael Polanyi (Thomas A. Langford and William H. Poteat, eds. Durham, NC: Duke UP, 1968) in Soundings 53. no. 1: 95-109. (4 journal offprints, 2 typescripts, 1 typescript copies, 1 manuscript), 1970 Spring (Box 25, Folder 389)
    - Review of Kierkegaard on Christ and Christian Coherence (Paul Sponheim. New York, Harper and Row, 1968.) in Dialog, 9: 67-70. (1 manuscript, 1 typescript)., 1970 Winter (Box 25, Folder 390)
    - Review of The Law-Gospel Debate (Gerhard O. Forde. Minneapolis: Augsburg, 1969) in Christian Century, 88: 727-728. (2 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 2 journals), 1971 Jun 9 (Box 25, Folder 391)
    - Review of Origins of European Thought (Richard Broxton. Arno.) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.2: 10. (1 copy of tear sheet, 1 typed manuscript, 1 manuscript, 1 letter from journal editor), 1974 Summer (Box 25, Folder 392)
    - Review of The Philosophy of Ernst Cassirer (Paul A. Schilpp. Open Court.) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.2: 10-11. (1 copy of tear sheet), 1974 Summer (Box 25, Folder 393)
    - Review of Process and Divinity (William Lewis Reese. LaSalle, IL: Open Court Pub. Co., 1964) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.2: 10-11. (1 copy of tear sheet, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript), 1974 Summer (Box 25, Folder 394)
    - Review of The False Messiah and Holier Than Thou (Clarence E. Ayres. Kelley, 1973) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.3: 8. (1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet, 1 typescript), 1974 Fall (Box 25, Folder 395)
    - Review of George Whitefield's Journals (George Whitefield. Scholars' Facsimiles and Reprints, 1969) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.4: 7 (Winter 1974-75). (1 tear sheet, 1 tear sheet copy, 1 manuscript, 1 copy of letter from journal editor), 1974-1975 Winter (Box 25, Folder 396)
    - Review of Idealism: A Critical Survey (A. C. Ewing. Barnes and Noble.) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Review, 19.4: 11. (1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet, 1 copy of letter from journal editor, 1 typed manuscript, 1 manuscript), 1974-1975 Winter (Box 25, Folder 397)
    - Review of Images of Hope (William Lynch. University of Notre Dame Press, 1974) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.4: 13. (1 copy of tear sheet, 1 tear sheet, 1 letter from journal editor), 1974-1975 Winter (Box 25, Folder 398)
    - Review of The Presence of Other Worlds (Wilson Van Dusen. New York: Harper and Row, 1974) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.4: 16 (2 copies of tear sheets, 1 copy of letter from journal editor), 1974-1975 Winter (Box 25, Folder 399)
    - Review of Transformation in Christ (Dietrich Von Hildebrand. Franciscan Herald Press, 1973) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.4: 16-17. (1 set of tear sheet copies, 1 copy of letter from journal editor), 1974-1975 Winter (Box 25, Folder 400)
    - Review of A Treatise of Morall Philosophile (William Baldwin. Scholars' Facsimiles and Reprints, 1967) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19:4: 11. (1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet, 1 copy of letter from journal editor), 1974-1975 Winter (Box 26, Folder 401)
    - Review of William James on Psychical Research (Gardner Murphy and Robert Ballou, comp and eds. New York: Viking Press, 1960) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 19.4. (1 copy of tear sheet, 1 tear sheet, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript), 1974-1975 Winter (Box 26, Folder 402)
    - Review of The Life of Adam (Giovanno F. Loredano. Scholars' Facsimiles and Reprints, 1967) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Review, 20.1. (1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet), 1975 Spring (Box 26, Folder 403)
    - Review of Myths and Dreams (Edward Clodd. Ann Arbor, MI: Gryphon Books, 1971) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 20.1:21. (1 manuscript, 1 typed manuscript, 1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet), 1975 Spring (Box 26, Folder 404)
    - Review of Perception (H. H. Price. Barnes and Noble, 1973) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 20.1. (1 set of tear sheet copies, 1 tear sheet), 1975 Spring (Box 26, Folder 405)
    - Review of The Religion of Nature Delineated (William Wollaston. Scholars' Facsimiles, 1974) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 20.1. (2 copies of journal reprint), 1975 Spring (Box 26, Folder 406)
    - "Irony Reconsidered." A review of A Rhetoric of Irony (Wayne C. Booth. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1974) and Irony (D.C. Muecke. London: Methuen, 1973) in Newsletter: Rhetoric Society of America, 5.3. (1 journal, 1 manuscript, 4 copies of typescript), 1975 Summer (Box 26, Folder 407)
    - Review of Homosexuality and the Western Christian Tradition (Derrick Sherwin Bailey. Archon) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Review, 20.1: 11. (1 copy of tear sheet), 1976 Spring (Box 26, Folder 409)
    - Review of Essays on Some of the First Principles of Metaphysicks, Ethics, and Theology (Asa Burton. Scholars' Facsimiles and Reprints, 1973) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Review, 20.4: 7. (2 typescripts, 1 manuscript, 1 copy of tear sheet), 1975-1976 Winter (Box 26, Folder 410)
    - Review of The First Tome of Volume of the Paraphrase of Erasmus upon the New Testament (Desiderius Erasmus. Delmar, NY: Scholars' Facsimilies and Reprints, 1975) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Review, 21.2: 8. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript, 1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet)., 1976 Summer (Box 26, Folder 411)
    - "Restless Spirit." A review of The Restless Quest (Julian N. Hartt. Philadelphia: United Church Press, 1975) in Religious Education, 71: 664-665. (2 typescripts, 1 copy of typescript, 1 manuscript), 1976 Nov-Dec (Box 26, Folder 412)
    - Review of Seasonable Thoughts on the State of Religion in New England (Charles Chauncy. Hicksville, N. Y.: Regina Press, 1975) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, XXI, no. 3: 973. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript, 1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet)., 1976 Fall (Box 26, Folder 413)
    - Review of Church and State in the United States (Philip Schaff. New York: Arno Press, 1972) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, XXII.1: 7. (3 copies of tear sheet, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1977 Spring (Box 26, Folder 414)
    - Review of Letters from Rome on the Council by Quirinus (Johann Joseph Ignaz von Dollinger. New York: Pott and Ambry, 1870) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 22.1: 27. (1 tear sheet, 2 copies of tear sheet, 1 manuscript, 1 typed manuscript), 1977 Spring (Box 26, Folder 415)
    - Review of A Woorke Concerning the Trewnesse of the Christian Religion (Philippe De Mornay. Scholars' Facsimiles and Reprints, Inc.) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, 22.2: 7. (1 tear sheet, 1 copy of tear sheet), 1977 Summer (Box 26, Folder 416)
    - Review of Horace Bushnell's Theory of Language, In the Context of Other Nineteenth-Century Philosophies of Language (Donald A. Crosby. The Hague: Monton and Co., 1975.) in Journal of the American Academy of Religion, 45.4: 521-522. (2 journal offprints, 2 typescripts, 1 manuscript)., 1977 Dec (Box 26, Folder 417)
    - Review of Christian Realism and Political Problems (Reinhold Niebuhr. New York: Scribner, 1953) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, XXII.4: 11. (1 journal photocopy, 1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., 1977-1978 Winter (Box 26, Folder 418)
    - Review of Spinoza Dictionary (Dagobert D. Runes. Westport, CT: Greenwood Press, 1951.) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, XXII.4: 6. (2 journal photocopies, 2 typescript)., 1977-1978 Winter (Box 26, Folder 419)
    - Review of Mysticism: A Study in the Nature of and Development of Man's Spiritual Consciousness (Evelyn Underhill. Totowa, NJ: Rowan and Littlefield, 1977) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, XXII: n.p. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript), 1978 (Box 26, Folder 420)
    - Review of Redemption: Three Sermons (Thomas Hooker. Gainsville, FL: Scholars' Facsimiles and Reprints, 1956) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, XXIII.3: 7. (1 journal excerpt copy, 1 manuscript, 1 typescript), 1978 (Box 26, Folder 421)
    - Review of The Person and Work of the Holy Spirit (Handley C.G. Moule. Dobbs Ferry, NY: Glanville Publishers, 1979) in Reprint Bulletin--Book Reviews, XXIV.2: 6. (1 typescript, 1 tear sheet, 1 manuscript)., 1979 Summer (Box 26, Folder 422)
    - Review of The Puritan Sermon in America, 1630-1750 (four-volume set) (Comp. by Ronald A. Bosco. Delmar, NY: Scholar's Facsimiles and Reprints, 1978.) in Reprint Bulletin--Book Reviews (orginal folder indicates Nov. 1979). (1 typescript, 1 manuscript, note from editor of journal?) (Box 26, Folder 423)
    - "About Theology and Faith: An Essay in Review" review of Progressive and Conservative Man (Herman H. Berger. Henry J. Koren, trans. Pittsburgh: Duquesne UP, 1971.) and Religion and Atheism (William A. Luijpen and Henry J. Koren. Pittsburgh: Duquesne UP, 1971.) and The Symbolic Language of Religion (Thomas Fawcett. Minneapolis: Augsburg, 1971.) Modern Christian Thought, From the Enlightenment to Vatican II (James C. Livingston. New York: Macmillan, 1971.) and Foundations of Theology (Gerald O'Collins, S.J. Chicago: Loyola UP, 1971.) Unpublished? (1 typescript, 1 manuscript). (Box 26, Folder 424)
    - Review of The Burden of Soren Kierkegaard (Edward John Carnell. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1965). Unpublished? (1 typescript, 1 printed review on same book by Clyde McCormack, with short note signed "Dick.") (Box 26, Folder 425)
    - "Comments About Darwin and the Bible ," a review of Darwin and the Bible ("Prof. Greene." Unpublished manuscript.) (3 typescripts, 1 manuscript) (Box 26, Folder 426)
    - Review of The Dawn of Personality (Emile Cailliet. New York: Bobbs-Merril Co., 1955) Unpublished? (1 typescript, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 427)
    - Review of Freedom and Grace (J. R. Lucas. London: SPCK, 1976) in Reprint Bulletin--Book Reviews (n.d.) (1 manuscript, 1 typescript). (Box 26, Folder 428)
    - "Remarks on From Science to Theology, A Metaphor " a review of From Science to Theology, A Metaphor. No publication information found on this book. Unpublished review? (3 typescripts) (Box 26, Folder 429)
    - Review of The Gospel of Suffering and The Lilies of the Field (Soren Kierkegaard. Minneapolis: Augsburg, 1948.) Unpublished? (n.d.) (Box 26, Folder 430)
    - Review of unnamed book about Karl Barth in the "Preacher's Library" series, most likely Karl Barth: An Introduction to His Early Theology, 1910-1931 (Thomas F. Torrance. London: SCM Press, 1962). Unpublished? (1 typescript) (Box 26, Folder 431)
    - Review of Kierkegaard e Nietzsche (Enrico Castelli, ed. Milano: Fratelli Bocca, 1953). Unpublished? (2 typescripts, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 432)
    - Review of Kierkegaard on Christ and Christian Coherence (Paul Sponheim. New York, Harper and Row, 1968.) Correspondence with Religion in Life, June 20, 1969. (1 typescript, 1 letter) (Box 26, Folder 433)
    - Review of Liberal Learning and Religion (Amos N. Wilder, ed. New York: Harpers and Bros., 1951.) Unpublished? (2 typescripts). (Box 26, Folder 434)
    - Review of The Life and Thought of Kierkegaard for Everyman (John A. Gates. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1960) in The Bookman. (1 typescript, letter). (Box 26, Folder 435)
    - "Review Comments Upon Hollwitz's The Mythoporic Act of C.S. Lewis ." Unpublished? (3 copies of transcripts, 1 manuscript), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 436)
    - Review of The Narrow Pass, A Study of Kierkegaard's Concept of Man (George Price. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1963.) Unpublished? (1 typescript, 1 manuscript)., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 437)
    - Review of On Kierkegaard: Philosophical Fragments (George J. Stack. Atlantic Highlands, N.J.: Humanities Press, 1976.) Unpublished? (1 typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 26, Folder 438)
    - "Report on John Dillenberger's Manuscript." (Unpublished?) (1 typescript, 1 manuscript) (Box 26, Folder 439)
    - Review of The Shape of the Christian Life (Nashville: Abingdon, 1969) reviewed for publisher. (2 typescripts, note from publisher), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 440)
    - Review of The Significance of Neoplatonism (Baine R. Harris. Albany: New York Press, 1976) in Reprint Bulletin--Book Reviews (original folder indicates 1978). (1 typescript, 1 manuscript). (Box 26, Folder 441)
    - "Some Problems of Contemporary Christian Thought" a review of Kerygma and History (Carl F. Braaten, ed. and trans. New York: Abingdon Press, 1962 and 1964) and The Philosopher and Theology (Etienne Gilson. Cecile Gilson, trans. New York: Random House, 1963) and Philosophical Fragments or A Fragment of Philosophy (Soren Kierkegaard. David F. Swenson, trans. Princeton, NJ: Princeton UP, 1962) in Yale Review 454-462. (2 typescripts, 2 manuscripts, 2 sets of tear sheets) (Box 26, Folder 442)
    - Review of Sprak och Logn (Stockholm: P.A. Norstedt and Soners Forlag, 1978). Unpublished? (1 typescript, 2 copies of typescripts, 1 letter from U of Chicago Press). (Box 26, Folder 443)
    - Review of What is Philosophy? (Dietrich von Hildebrand. Franciscan Herald Press, 1973) in Reprint Bulletin-Book Reviews, n.v.: n.p. (1 typescript, 1 manuscript). (Box 26, Folder 444)
    - Review of Wittgenstein--The Later Philosophy, An Exposition of the "Philosophical Investigations" (Atlantic Highlands, NJ: Humanities Press, 1977) Unpublished review? (1 manuscript) (Box 26, Folder 445)
    - Review of Wittgenstein's Doctrine of the Tyranny of Language; an Historical and Critical Examination of His Blue Book (S. Morris Engel. The Hague: Nijhoff, 1971) Unpublished review? (1 typescript, notes) (Box 26, Folder 446)
- Notes by Holmer, n.d.; Series II
  - "About God and Analytic Philosophy" - Outline (Box 26, Folder 447)
  - "Administrative Thought" - Notes, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 448)
  - "American History: 1620-1837"; Notes/Outlines- Lecture notes - 10/2/38 - 12/7/38), 1938 (Box 26, Folder 449)
  - American History -American History class notes (taken by Holmer by a student or by another student?): chronological charts, reading notes, lecture notes; "The Opening of the Crystal Palace," a seminar aassignment -- March 7, 1989, 1989, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 450)
  - American History - American History class notes (taken by Holmer by a student or by another student?): reading notes roughly from 1865 to FDR and New Deal, 1939 U.S. Map, print of Bingham's "Daniel Boone's Party Approaching the Valley from Cumberland Gap" (Box 26, Folder 450)
  - "Apostle Paul" - Notes/Outlines ("The Life of Paul," "Paul's Commission," "Paul and the Jews," "Thinking with the Apostle Paul,"; "Jesus," "I Cor. 1-3"); Other (New York Times - 11/19/93 - "Victims and Enemies, Groping Toward Peace [Israeli/Palestinian conflicts]), 1993, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 451)
  - "Barth and the Logic of Belief" - Outline (Box 27, Folder 451)
  - "Barth on 'Consciousness'" - Outline, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 452)
  - "Belief" - Outlines ("On Believing in God," "On Believing the Scriptures"), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 454)
  - "Belief " - Outlines ("The Groundlessness of Belief," "The Character of Belief: W and K," Xian Belief) (Box 27, Folder 455)
  - "Chaucer, Geoffrey" - Notes/Outlines ("Dates [from 1265 to 1450]," "Characteristics of the Author [Chaucer?]," "Chaucer," "Characterization," notes on Canterbury Tales, "Chaucer and Religion" (Box 27, Folder 456)
  - "Concepts and S. Kierkegaard" - Outline (Box 27, Folder 457)
  - "Contemporary Philosophy" - Notes/Outlines ("Contemporary Philosophy," "Philosophical Notions in Creative Evolution ," "Pragmatists in General," "Treatment of Universals - Bergson," "Berkeley - Hume as Critics"), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 458)
  - "Crimes, Wrongs, and Sin" - Notes/Outlines ("Lonch [?], A.R. 'Sins and Crimes'," "Ronald Duorkin [?], 'Lord Devlin [?] and the Enforcement of Morals'") (Box 27, Folder 459)
  - "The Crisis in Theology" - Notes for a projected article: "What is Theology?" "Ideas for Theology Paper," "Theologians and Their Language" (Box 27, Folder 460)
  - "Culture" - Outlines ("Christianity and Modern Culture," "K. and Ind. Existence," "What says Xianity about all this?" "Passion and Jesus Christ," "Kierkegaard and Social Existence") (Box 27, Folder 461)
  - "Darwin and Theology" - Outline (Box 27, Folder 462)
  - "Dicta about Pastoral Counseling and Being a Professor" - Outline (Box 27, Folder 462)
  - "Dismantling ... Pride" - Outline for lecture, notes on relevent scripture passages, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 463)
  - "Dispositions" - Outlines ("Educating Our Dispositions," "Making Sense Christianly: Intellectually"), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 464)
  - "Doctrines" - Notes/Outlines ("Bibliography of Sources on Doctrines and Preaching on Doctrines," "Topics for Doctrinal Preaching," "Thanksgiving," "Jesus Christ - 'Judge of the Quick and the Dead'," "Last Judgement," "Notes on Preaching," "Advent and Second Coming," "Holy Spirit," "Sermon on Holy Spirit," "Doctrine of God," "Doctrinal Preaching") (Box 27, Folder 465)
  - "Does Anyone Know God?" - Outline, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 466)
  - "Dread" - Outlines ("The Concept of Dread," "Kierkegaard and Logic," eternity, "The Concept of Dread -- and Logic") (Box 27, Folder 467)
  - "Emotions, Passions, Feelings" - Outlines ("Emotions, Passions, Feelings"; "Making Sense of One's Life"; "About Emotions and Forms of Life"; "More About Emotion and Forms of Life"; "About Emotions and the Law (Ethics)"; "Emotions and X'n Faith"); Other (Hymn -- "Higher Ground" by Johnson Oatman, Jr.) (Box 27, Folder 468)
  - "Epistemology" - Notes/Outlines ("Montague, The Ways of Knowing ," "Critical Realists," "The New Realism," "Hyper-Syllogism," "Methods on Rat. and Emp.") (Box 27, Folder 469)
  - "Facts and Logic" - Outlines ("About Facts and Theology," "About Logic and Logicality," "Logic: Historical Remarks," "J.R. Lucas 'On Not Worshipping Facts'," "Aristotle and Math of Opposites") (Box 27, Folder 470)
  - "Family" - Outlines ("Birth Control," "Birth Rates and Social Life," "The Meaning of the Industrial Revolution," "The Problems in the Modern Family," "The Woman in England,"etc. (Box 27, Folder 471)
  - "Gilson, Etienne" - Notes ("Chapter II - Faith and Reason); Other ("Selected Writings of Etienne Gilson") (Box 27, Folder 472)
  - "Gilson, Etienne" - Outlines ("Conception of Science in the Modern World," "Strictly Scientific Contribution of Psychoanalysis," class list, "Emphasis upon Existence," "Questions on Gilson's Book," "Gilson: Being and Some Philosophers," etc. (Box 27, Folder 473)
  - "Godliness" - Sermon notes on II Timothy 3:5-7, given on 8/21/94 at Bad Medicine Lake, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 474)
  - "Hagerstrom, Axel" - Toentman's copy - Chart [in Swedish or Danish?] that covers dates 1903-1941, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 478)
  - "Harnack" - Outline, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 479)
  - "Hosea" - Notes/Outlines ("Hosea 11-14," "Necessity for a Political Religion [?]," "1st three chapters [of Hosea]," "Notes about the areas wars," "Word of the Lord"), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 480)
  - "Ibsen" - Notes/Outlines ("Ibsen's Plays in Chronological Order," "The Anglo-Sw [?] Foundation's," "Henrick Ibsen: 1828-1906," "Pillars of Soc.," "Shaw's Quintessence of Ibsenism ," "Ibsens life 27 yrs. out of Norway," " Ghosts ," " The Feast at Solhaug - Ibsen," " Lady Inger of Ostriat - Ibsen," " Little Eyolf - Ibsen," " When We Dead Awaken - Ibsen," "Archibald Henderson's European Dramatists (Box 27, Folder 481)
  - "Jaspers, Karl" - Notes/Outlines ("Contents of Phil. Faith," "Jaspers and Philosophy," "Jaspers' Attack," "Concepts of Existentialism," "The Independent Philosopher," "Traditional Philosophy," "Jaspers' Philosophy re: Present Day Man," etc. (Box 27, Folder 482)
  - "Jesus in a Manger" - Notes; outline for lecture; copy of hymn "Rejoice, Rejoice, Believers!", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 483)
  - "Kant" - Notes/Outlines from student era, 1942-1943 (Box 27, Folder 484)
  - "Kierkegaard, Soren" - Notes, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 489)
  - "Kierkegaard, Soren" - Notes, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 490)
  - "Kierkegaard, Soren" - Notes, 1945, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 491)
  - "Kierkegaard, Soren" - Notes, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 492)
  - "Kierkegaard, Soren"- Notes, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 493)
  - "Knowledge of God" - Notes/Outlines ("Theology," "C.S. Lewis on Theol. God," "Revelation and Knowing God," "Paradox," "Knowing God," "About Theology," "Theology as Grammar," "Knowledge of God," "Theology and Knowing God") (Box 27, Folder 494)
  - "Learning" - Notes/Outlines ("On Learning," "About Learning"), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 495)
  - "Lewis, H.D." - Outlines (Lewis [lecture 1], "Ethics and Religion" [lecture 6], Lewis [lecture 5] - Other ("Bibliography of Recent Works in the Philosophy of Religion") (Box 27, Folder 496)
  - "Living with Dying" - Outline, info for the Third Annual Spring Oncology Seminar -- Spartanburg, SC, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 497)
  - "Logic" - Notes/Outlines ("Range of the Variable = Universe of Discourse," "W.V. Quinn - Elementary Logic," "Class and Class Membership," "Dilemmas," "Exercises 5 and 6," etc. (Box 27, Folder 498)
  - Logic - Notes/Outlines ("Syllogism: Categorical," "Fallacies in Syllogistic Form," "Some unintelligent fail to get this," "Figures and Moods," "Syllogisms,"" - Holmer's Completed Student Examinations -- four blue books, etc. (Box 27, Folder 499)
  - "Logic and Language: Uses and Meaning" - Outline for Part II: Logical Problems (Box 27, Folder 500)
  - "Luther and Music" - Notes/Outlines (Box 28, Folder 501)
  - "Making Sense of Life and Learning" - Outlines, flyer for U of MN lecture -- 11/14/1996 (Box 28, Folder 502)
  - "Memory and Renewal" -Notes - Program for a Luther Songfest (Box 28, Folder 503)
  - "The Minister and Philosophy" - Outline (Box 28, Folder 504)
  - "Music and the Lutheran Heritage" - Outline (Box 28, Folder 505)
  - "New Moralities and Old: A Reconsideration" - Outlines, notes; Danish newspaper clippings re: Kierkegaard (Box 28, Folder 506)
  - "On Believing the Bible" - Notes/Outlines ("Authority of Scripture," "Criticism - Bible," "Bible," "On Believing the Scripture," "The objective pattern of things," "Luther [on scripture]," "The Scripture and the Present 5 [?]" (Box 28, Folder 507)
  - "On Christian Emotions" - Notes for a six-part series given at Augsburg College - Other (program - 11/3 - 11/11, hymn - "I Have a Future All Sublime"), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 508)
  - "Philosophical Theology" -- General - Notes/Outlines (''Scripture and Theology," "Two Kinds of Extremes in Philosophy and Theology," "The End of the Middle Ages," "What Theology Means and Does," "Some Important Questions," "On Meaning," "Ordinary Language," "What is Theology?" "The Nature of Theology," "'History' and 'Theology'," "God and His Nature," "Renewal of the Church") (Box 28, Folder 509)
  - "Philosophical Theology" -- God and Necessary BeliefNotes/Outlines ("Is it Necessary to Believe Explicitly?" "Some Considerations about 'God's Existence'," "Thomas' Argument," "Is It Necessary to Believe Explicitly?" "About Explicit Believing," "Theses About Four Possibilities," "God's Existence" (Box 28, Folder 510)
  - "Philosophy and Religion"- Notes; "Philosophizing About Religion" (projected textbook outline) (Box 28, Folder 511)